<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-01T20:08:22+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Home</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/Introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/Introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/Introduction.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DcYS6XfWbL8"><img src="https://thepigeonpress.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/the-tree-of-life.png" alt="Alt text" /></a>
<small><em>Project trailer, click the thumbnail to get redirected to Youtube</em><small></small></small></p>

<p>For a while now, we’ve been hearing about CO2 emissions, their dangers for the future of our planet, and for us who inhabit it. Every day, a TV in the background, a radio, or a voice on the street warns us of the dangers we’re facing, of the inevitable death spiral we’ve entered, of the irreversibility of our actions on the environment. It’s become such a daily white noise that it almost doesn’t scare us anymore, its effects not yet tangibly catastrophic enough to despair our concern. <br /> Some are trying to change course and mitigate the damage. <br /> Others continue undisturbed to operate as they always have, testing the planet’s patience.</p>

<h3 id="but-where-are-we-really"><em>But where are we really?</em><br /></h3>
<h3 id="are-we-truly-plunging-into-the-abyss-"><em>Are we truly plunging into the abyss?</em> <br /></h3>
<h3 id="what-are-the-direct-factors-that-most-influence-co2-emissions-and-what-are-the-socioeconomic-factors-that-indirectly-influence-this-problem-"><em>What are the direct factors that most influence CO2 emissions, and what are the socioeconomic factors that indirectly influence this problem?</em> <br /></h3>

<p>With this research, we aimed to answer these questions by passionately delving into the global evolution of CO2 emissions over space and time, to understand where we started from and the current situation. The research then continues in the subsequent chapters with an analysis of the factors directly influencing CO2 emissions and proceeds with a chapter dedicated to exploring external factors that indirectly affect this issue, such as global governance forms, the level of education of the population, etc., with the aim of uncovering new patterns and correlations.</p>

<p>For the curious ones, the primary dataset used for the analysis is provided by <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/">Our World In Data</a>, offering a vast collection of data from 1900 to the present day. Each entry in the dataset represents a country in a specific year, with information regarding population, fuels usage, CO2 emissions per capita, contribution to the global warming and many more. In addition to this extensive dataset, we relied on external sources to gather global socioeconomic data and intersect this information with that of the initial dataset, in order to obtain a more comprehensive overview capable of meeting our objectives.</p>

<p>With the hope that this analysis opens your mind and leaves you with something to ponder, as it has done for us, <br />we wish you a good read.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project trailer, click the thumbnail to get redirected to Youtube]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our contribution to global warming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/GlobalWarming.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our contribution to global warming" /><published>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/GlobalWarming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/GlobalWarming.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://postimg.cc/D8bMtWCy"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/m2dW1CCM/Whats-App-Image-2024-05-01-at-19-49-39.jpg" alt="Whats-App-Image-2024-05-01-at-19-49-39.jpg" /></a>
<small>Burmeister &amp; Wain’s shipyard in Copenhagen, Denmark<small></small></small></p>

<p>Temperatures on Earth have been rising since the Industrial Revolution (1760-1840). While natural variability plays some part, the preponderance of evidence indicates that human activities—particularly emissions of heat-trapping <strong>greenhouse gases</strong>—are mostly responsible for making our planet warmer. 
According to <a href="https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/">NASA - GISS</a> which is an ongoing study on temperature analysis, the average global temperature on Earth has increased by at least 1.1° Celsius (1.9° Fahrenheit) since 1880. The majority of the warming has occurred since <strong>1975</strong>, at a rate of roughly 0.15 to 0.20°C per decade. 
Within this context, our analysis focuses on quantifying the specific contribution of each country of greenhouse gas emissions to this observed temperature increase. By examining the relationship between greenhouse gas emissions and temperature changes over the past century, we aim to explain the extent to which human activities have influenced the Earth’s climate system.</p>

<div class="flourish-embed flourish-hierarchy" data-src="visualisation/17792609"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div>

<p>In the beginning of the 20th century, not surprisingly, United States was the leading country in terms of rising the global temperature. The US contributed with 0.04°C, which, indeed is a big part of the contribution as we saw before that the planet is getting warmer by 0.15 to 0.20°C per decade. This contribution was followed by United Kingdom, Russia and Germany, each of them contributing a 0.01°C per the year 1901.</p>

<p>How did the US contribute x4 times more than countries such as UK, Germany or Russia? Let’s dive into history…</p>

<p><a href="https://postimg.cc/14ddC0rj"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/QxNrM09h/Whats-App-Image-2024-05-01-at-19-50-33.jpg" alt="Whats-App-Image-2024-05-01-at-19-50-33.jpg" /></a>
<small>Ford Motor Company’s Revolution 1913<small></small></small></p>

<p>By 1878 the United States had reentered a period of prosperity after the long depression of the mid-1870s. In the ensuing 20 years the volume of industrial production, the number of workers employed in industry, and the number of manufacturing plants all more than doubled.
The expansion of the iron and steel industry was even more impressive: from 1880 to 1900 the annual production of steel in the United States went from about 1,400,000 to more than 11,000,000 tons. Before the end of the century, <strong>the United States surpassed Great Britain.</strong></p>

<p>in the production of iron and steel and was providing more than <strong>one-quarter of the world’s supply of pig iron</strong>.</p>

<h1 id="so-how-far-have-we-gone-from-the-beginning-of-the-20th-century-until-the-year-2021-"><em><center>So, how far have we gone from the beginning of the 20th century until the year 2021? </center></em></h1>

<p>Let’s see how the current top contributing countries have contributed to the global temperature over the years.</p>

<iframe src="https://gorgeous-elk.static.domains/temperature_change_plot.html " width="100%" height="600px"></iframe>

<p>As can be seen the situation has not changed much compared to the past. All countries have followed an upward trend in contributing to the increase in global surface temperature. The US continues to lead the way with the incredible development of its industry. In addition, it is interesting to note that in 1996 Russia was overtaken by China, now the second largest contributor in terms of temperature. Why did China overtake Russia? Let’s take a look:</p>

<p><a href="https://postimg.cc/pyr7Jczj"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/qBxT0971/Whats-App-Image-2024-05-01-at-19-50-53.jpg" alt="Whats-App-Image-2024-05-01-at-19-50-53.jpg" /></a>
<small>Jiang Zemin and Boris Yeltsin in 1996</small></p>

<p>In 1996, China surpassed Russia in terms of greenhouse gas emissions, consequently impacting global temperatures. This shift was propelled by China’s rapid industrial and economic growth during the 1990s, driven by expansion in manufacturing, construction, and energy sectors. Meanwhile, Russia’s economic transition following the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991 may have temporarily reduced industrial production and emissions. Additionally, Russia’s economic and political challenges during this period could have hindered its capacity to monitor and regulate emissions effectively. 
<a href="https://www.britannica.com/event/Kyoto-Protocol">Global shifts in energy and environmental policies, such as the impending Kyoto Protocol</a> of 1997, which imposed emission reduction targets on developed nations, may have influenced China and Russia’s emission behaviors.</p>

<p>In conclusion, currently in the year 2024, different countries and continents will adopt measures to curb the creation of greenhouse gases such as the <a href="https://www.imo.org/es/MediaCentre/PressBriefings/pages/MEPC76.aspx">Ban on heavy fuel oil in the Arctic</a> as of July 1, 2024, which states that ships may not use or transport heavy fuel oil as fuel in Arctic waters. 
But certainly, there is still a long way to go and it will be long, unfortunately, not all countries have the necessary measures in place to fight climate change. World organizations must fight together to stop the climate catastrophe and ban those who do not follow the stipulated regulations.</p>

<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<p><a href="https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/">https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/</a>
<a href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/world-of-change/global-temperatures">https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/world-of-change/global-temperatures</a>
<a href="https://www.britannica.com/event/Kyoto-Protocol">https://www.britannica.com/event/Kyoto-Protocol</a>
<a href="https://www.imo.org/es/MediaCentre/PressBriefings/pages/MEPC76.aspx">https://www.imo.org/es/MediaCentre/PressBriefings/pages/MEPC76.aspx</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Burmeister &amp; Wain’s shipyard in Copenhagen, Denmark]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Over time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/AnalysisOverTime.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Over time" /><published>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/AnalysisOverTime</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/AnalysisOverTime.html"><![CDATA[<div class="flourish-embed flourish-bar-chart-race" data-src="visualisation/17641009"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div>
<p>Our analysis starts from <strong>1900</strong>, until the present day, and considers all <strong>193 states</strong> of the world. The CO2 emissions of each state in a specific year are measured in million tonnes, or more easily, in billions of kilograms. 
This is a million of tonnes: <br /></p>
<h1 id="1000000000-kg"><em><center>1.000.000.000 kg</center></em></h1>
<p><br />
 Almost all items in the dataset used exclude emissions caused by <strong>changes in land use</strong> , i.e., they do not take into account the effects of activities such as deforestation, conversion of forests into agricultural or urban land, wetland reclamation, reforestation. This approach allows to isolate the impact of direct human activities on CO2 emissions, providing a more specific view of the trends in emissions related to industry and energy.</p>

<p>At the beginning of the 19th century, the global situation was as follows:
<a href="https://postimg.cc/9r5H5n07"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/sD1jSFRw/top20-co2-1901.png" alt="top20-co2-1901.png" /></a><br />
<small><em><center> Top 20 countries for CO2 emissions in 1901</center></em><small></small></small></p>

<p>It’s no surprise to see the leading positions, with the United States leading with 721 million tons of CO2 emitted into the air, caused by the rapid industrialization and economic expansion they were undergoing at that time. Similarly, the United Kingdom had been the first country to experience the Industrial Revolution in the 18th century, while Germany had made coal its primary source of energy after the discovery of rich deposits in the Ruhr region.
It is then crucial to note that Poland, in fourth position, was not yet a state in 1901 but was divided between the Russian Empire, the German Empire, and the Austro-Hungarian Empire. Its 67 billion emitted tons were due to mining extraction and industrial activities carried out by the major empires.</p>

<p><a href="https://postimg.cc/tnq48tzw"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/tJPnZBnq/ww1co2.png" alt="ww1co2.png" /></a>
<small><em><center> CO2 emissions from 1900 to 1930</center></em><small></small></small></p>

<p>As visible in the graph above, the positive trend continues in the following two decades, and quite surprisingly, the year of the outbreak of the First World War does not represent a peak for emissions. Instead, it registers a decrease compared to the previous year. We had thought that the efforts employed for the production of war materials would have positively influenced emissions.</p>

<p>At the end of the conflict, many nations experienced economic recession or financial instability, which predictably caused a decrease in emissions. However, this rebounded quickly over the course of the decade, until the year of the Great Depression, 1929.</p>

<p>As well-known, and confirmed by the following interactive graph, the United States experienced a dramatic crisis, with CO2 emissions decreasing by almost 36%. This crisis also reflected across the ocean, mainly in Germany, where emissions decreased by 35%. The collapse of industrial production and the growth of social discontent contributed to the political success of the Nazi party.</p>

<iframe src="https://gorgeous-elk.static.domains/plot_co2_1945.html" width="100%" height="600px"></iframe>
<p><small>CO2 emissions of selected countries from 1901 to 1950. Click on the legend to show or hide a specific country</small></p>

<p>It can be observed from the same interactive graph, if we focus solely on Germany, how Adolf Hitler’s rise to power led CO2 emissions to their historical highs, with a peak of 670 million tons of CO2 emitted in 1943, thanks to the significant expansion of steel industries, war industries, and the massive exploitation of German coal mines.</p>

<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/0b/RIAN_archive_348_During_the_siege.jpg" alt="Alt text" /><br />
<small><em>Russian women working in city factory in Leningrad during WWII</em><small></small></small></p>

<p>The war devastated all countries, but it’s particularly interesting to note how Germany’s CO2 emissions dropped from 600 million tons emitted in 1944 to 116 in 1945.</p>
<h1 id="this-represents-a-decrease-of-almost-80-in-just-one-year"><em><center>This represents a decrease of almost 80% in just one year</center></em></h1>

<p>Dopo la seconda guerra mondiale , è interessante spostare il focus su due stati in particolare che scalarono le classifiche in termini di emissioni di CO2 a una velocità incredibile. Stiamo parlando di Cina e Russia (all’epoca Unione Sovietica), e in termini minori, il Giappone.
La Russia, sotto il governo di Khrushchev e successivamente di Gorbachev, ha aumentato in maniera quasi lineare le sue emissioni di CO2, assumendo nel 1958 la seconda posizione mondiale come maggiori emettitori di CO2, con 808 milioni di tonnellate, sotto i 2747 di milioni emessi dalla capolista Stati Uniti. Ciò fu dovuto al programma di industrializzazione su vasta scala per modernizzare l’economia e raggiungere il livello di sviluppo dei paesi occidentali. E dal conteggio di questa analisi sono escluse le emissioni causate dalle politiche di politiche di collettivizzazione agricola, che hanno portato alla conversione di vaste aree di terre per uso agricolo intensivo.
Dal 1958 al 1989 la Russia mantiene la medaglia d’argento in termini di emissioni aumentando in quei 30 anni del 68%.
In seguito alla caduta del muro di Berlino e alla dissoluzione dell’Unione Sovietica, la drastica caduta di emissioni è visibile nel grafico interattivo qui sotto, che mette la Russia in confronto con Cina e Giappone.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our analysis starts from 1900, until the present day, and considers all 193 states of the world. The CO2 emissions of each state in a specific year are measured in million tonnes, or more easily, in billions of kilograms. This is a million of tonnes: 1.000.000.000 kg Almost all items in the dataset used exclude emissions caused by changes in land use , i.e., they do not take into account the effects of activities such as deforestation, conversion of forests into agricultural or urban land, wetland reclamation, reforestation. This approach allows to isolate the impact of direct human activities on CO2 emissions, providing a more specific view of the trends in emissions related to industry and energy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conclusion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/Conclusion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conclusion" /><published>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T09:41:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/Conclusion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/Conclusion.html"><![CDATA[<p>prova gh_pages con KAGAMIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII
You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[prova gh_pages con KAGAMIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contributions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/contributions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contributions" /><published>2024-04-28T09:30:05+02:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T09:30:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/contributions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/worldCO2_SocialData_FinalProject/jekyll/update/2024/04/28/contributions.html"><![CDATA[<p>prova gh_pages con KAGAMIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII
You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[prova gh_pages con KAGAMIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry></feed>